[
  {
    "question": "Each cell of the ______ tissue is capable of giving rise to a microspore tetrad.",
    "answer": "sporogenous"
  },
  {
    "question": "Each one is a potential pollen or microspore ______ cell.",
    "answer": "mother"
  },
  {
    "question": "The process of formation of microspores from a pollen mother cell through ______ is called microsporogenesis.",
    "answer": "meiosis"
  },
  {
    "question": "The microspores are arranged in a cluster of four cells called the microspore ______.",
    "answer": "tetrad"
  },
  {
    "question": "As the anthers mature and ______, the microspores dissociate from each other.",
    "answer": "dehydrate"
  },
  {
    "question": "The microspores develop into ______ grains.",
    "answer": "pollen"
  },
  {
    "question": "Inside each ______ several thousands of microspores or pollen grains are formed.",
    "answer": "microsporangium"
  },
  {
    "question": "The pollen grains are released with the ______ of anther.",
    "answer": "dehiscence"
  },
  {
    "question": "Pollen grains represent the male ______.",
    "answer": "gametophytes"
  },
  {
    "question": "The opened anthers of ______ or any other flower deposit yellowish pollen grains on your fingers.",
    "answer": "Hibiscus"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sprinkle pollen grains on a drop of ______ taken on a glass slide to observe under a microscope.",
    "answer": "water"
  },
  {
    "question": "Pollen grains from different species show a variety of architecture in sizes, shapes, colours, and ______.",
    "answer": "designs"
  }
]
